

# **ABOUT ME**

Creative and innovative SAP ABAP HANA certified professional with 12 years of experience & demonstrated track record in design, implementation, technical upgrades, cloud migrations and AMS support of SAP.

Integration specialist with SAP CPI for SuccessFactors and SAP ARIBA CIG.

Visionary leader recognized for advanced team building capability, accelerated business acumen, and pragmatic problem-solving approaches.

Adaptive critical thinker ability to work in with various business units to define, justify and prioritize business requirements in a global and cross culture environment with strong interpersonal, communication, and leadership skills.

# LinkedIn:

# **NAZEER** HUSSAIN

SAP TECHNICAL LEAD



nazeerhussain.58@gmail.com

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **IBM SAUDI ARABIA** (SUB CO -DAR/MASSADR)

Jubail Oct 2016- Present

# **SAP Technical Lead**

- · Architecture design & merging multiple SAP applications for two organizations to single system.
- BRF+ For MDG
- HANATIZATION of the ABAP programs
- Upgrade activity for migration of SAP systems to Business Suite on Hana.
- AMS support for multiple SAP modules. (MM, SD, FICO, HCM, VIM, BCM, PP, PM, QM & EHS)
- Configuration & activation of standard SAP Fiori applications.
- Integration of SucessFactors and ECC using SAP CPI
- SAP Ariba integration CIG
- EHSM Techno functional: Incident Management & Safety Observation

# **BEST APPLICATIONS FOR IT**

Jubail Aug 2014- Sep 2016

#### **SAP Technical Consultant**

- Unification of sales and shipment documentation.
- Enhancement Alignment Sales automation process, credit management process, quotation approval.
- · Down payment approval process in Fiori
- Delegation Fiori app
- Positive time recording Implementation
- Open text VIM Support Project
- Enhancement- PP reconciliation
- Riyadh Bank BCM WPS Roll out

## KAAR TECHNOLOGIES

Chennai India / Jubail Saudi Arabia Aug 2013- Aug 2014

#### **SAP ABAP Consultant**

- Implementation Roll out PBT Plant (ALE IDOC)
- Webdynpro applications
- Military Industry Corporation KSA Implementation

## TVS INFOTECH

Chennai India Dec 2010- July 2013

#### **SAP ABAP Consultant**

- KCP Sugars implementation
- Sundram Fasteners Zhejiang Limited Implementation,
- Sundram Fasteners SAP ECC Financial Consolidation & Vendor Payments Implementation
- Sundram Fasteners Interactive and Retail portal in SAP ECC 6.0
- Rajshree Sugars & Chemical Ltd, Chennai Implementation Cane Management System in SAP ECC

# **EDUCATION**

#### **VTU BELGAUM**

India 2010

**Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science** 

SJCIT (2006-2010)

# **SKILLS**

- SAP ABAP & HANA ABAP
- SAP Ariba CIG
- SAP Workflow & Webdynpro
- SAP CPI SucessFactors Integration
- FPM & BRF+
- SAP FIORI Odata

# **CERTIFICATION**

- SAP Certified Associate ABAP with Netweaver 7.0
- SAP Certified Specialist ABAP for SAP HANA 2.0
- SAP Certified Application Associate SAP Cloud Platform Integration

# **Projects:**

#### At IBM KSA:

Client	Saudi International Petrochemical Company Saudi Arabia
Duration	September 2016 to till Date
Role	SAP Technical Lead & EHS/EHSM Techno Functional Consultant
Industry	Petrochemical
Onsite/Offsite	Onsite

# AMS | Oct 2016 - Till Date

- Ariba Integration gateway support.
- SucessFactors integration support
- Medical Insurance claim acceptance Fiori app.
- EHS Dashboards with SAC.
- EHSM rollout Incident, Near Miss & Safety observation process. Revamping FPM applications.
- Cashflow & Trial balance reports for SIPCHEM Europe.
- MRR process.
- COPA report
- Periodic GL balance report for BCG.
- Detailed notification to customer during invoice release to accounting.
- QM COA.
- Customer Block unblock process with notification and attachments.
- HR Merit report for BPC submission
- SAP Cloud platform Integration for SucessFactors Employee Central to ERP Org assignment
- 4X4 and Manager Time Deduction Application
- OT pre-approval process with workflow approval
- Benefits and plans Fiori App Validations
- Developed ABAP Managed Database Procedures (AMDP) and Core Data services (CDS).
- Developed IDA report
- Enhanced the existing reports using the Advanced SQL Concepts of EHP7 on HANA.
- Setting up base line configurations for change request type in process modelling
- Single and Parallel workflow configuration in BRFplus
- Configured BRFplus workflow for vendor and material master change request types (10 CR types)
- Configured Mail Notification on each approval step to notify user

#### **EHS Functional Role**

- SAP EHS Consultant and part of AMS team.
- SIPCHEM SAHARA Merger Implementation project for Incident Management, Safety Observation, Occupational Health.
- Preparation of AS-IS, TO-BE document, review & signoff.
- Customization changes as per the change management.
- Prepare Test scripts for EHS T-Codes
- Realization/ customizing of EHS Components for Occupational Health (OH)
- Perform system testing and support users in user acceptance testing
- (UAT) / Final Integration Testing
- Preparation of EHS end user training manuals.
- Training for identified End Users & Power users.
- Medical service integrated with outlook calendar.
- Enhanced the Incident reporting screen as per Sipchem business process with FPM & BOPF.
- Separate screens for Incidents, Near Miss and Safety observation.
- EHSM Incident Management EHSM Incident and Near Miss reporting application which allows Employees, Contractors across the organization to record incidents, near misses, Classify, Investigate and assign tasks.
- Classification (Sponsor) of Incident/Near miss as separate entity and same integrated with the incident process.
- EHSM Safety Observation New Observation system for reporting all observations including the unsafe acts, unsafe condition and Safe Observation, reviewing the Observation, assigning tasks, approving task and closing the observation.
- Automation and Escalation at each stage for better tracking.
- Enhanced the system to achieve Incident Gatekeeper process based on the incident groups.

# Merger (SIPCHEM & SAHARA Petrochemical) | Jun 2019 - Jan 2020

- SPAU and SPDD activity.
- Involved in Hanatization of all custom programs with reference to HANA DB syntax.
- Inbound and outbound Idoc Integration with LYB for Order Ack, delivery confirmation, shipment advice and Invoice.
- Unification of sales and shipment documentation.
- Enhancement Alignment Sales automation process, credit management process, quotation approval.
- Technical Evaluation Process.
- Down payment approval process in Fiori
- FI Asset disposal Fiori app
- Delegation Fiori app

# Support | Oct 2016 - May 2019

- Positive time recording support
- Employee Shift substitution using WDA
- SD, MM, FI-CO, PP, PM, QM, HR, open text VIM Support issues
- SF integration
- Sales Dashboard with Power BI application
- WPS
- PPE for safety using WDA
- Material gate pass application in SAP
- PR approval Fiori app enhancement
- Custom FIORI app and ODATA Service for BCM Batch approval and Employee course booking approval.
- Extension of PO approval FIORI application.

# At Best Applications:

Client	Saudi International Petrochemical Company Saudi Arabia	
Duration	November 2013 to August 2016	
Role	Technical Consultant	
Industry	Petrochemical	
Onsite/Offsite	Onsite	

## **Support | Jun 2016 - August 2016**

- Lookup RFC to update file reference in ECC for Pl.
- COA Form.
- HR Employee transfer program with input from excel

#### Open text VIM Support Project | March 2016 - May 2016

- Non-PO and PO invoice determination exit to check the incoming invoice
- Escalation Mail notifications for pending work items to supervisors.
- Auto applying rules functionality for processed work items.

# SAP Positive Time Recording Project | May 2015 - Feb 2016

- Establish connectivity between Kaba Time Recording Terminals & SAP using standard HR-PDC interface
- Employee ID card issuance/renewal & lost process in WDA with multi-level approval workflow.
- Clock-in / Clock-out regularization by employees with approval from direct supervisor
- Automate generation of overtime quota for employees based on clock-in / clock-out
- Dynamic shift substitution in WDA and Workflow for the approval.
- Automate late coming / early going deduction & penalties

# Upgrade- HEBA Fire & Safety | February 2015 - April 2015

• Handled all the ABAP upgrade issues SPAU & SPDD.

### Enhancement- PP reconciliation | November 2014 - January 2015

- Developed report to display the batch wise bulk material production.
- Developed report to display the batch wise bagged/finished material production.

# Riyadh Bank – BCM WPS Roll out / HR Forms Support | Aug 2014 – November 2014

- Interface development and mapping in SAP PI to the bank third party system.
- Developed enhancement for the existing BCM file to setup WPS (Wage Protection System) compliant payroll file to be sent to Riyadh Bank using BCM. (FBPM1 and BNK\_MONI transactions) **WPS & MOL compliant files**

# At Kaar Technologies:

# Implementation – Roll out PBT Plant (ALE IDOC) | March 2014 – June 2014

- WMTORD, Storage unit type and BENUM addition/populating.
- Relocation to Scrap From Viad@t to SAP with Immediate confirmation at SAP, without TO trigger
- Sap Physical Inventory set up based on Transfer Order need 701 or 702 with + ve or -ve value in the quantity.
- Enhanced inbound WHSCON populate container number in delivery.

# SIPCHEM ECC Support | Nov 2013 - Feb 2014

- Developed a payroll function for calculating Housing Allowance
- Developed a webdynpro application for Training history report for HR module.
- Developed Smartform form for Purchase Order from SAP script.

# Military Industry Corporation KSA Implementation | Aug 2013 – Oct 2013

• Developed Attendance/Absence detail RFC in HRMS module.

#### At TVS infotech:

# KCP Sugars implementation | March 2013 – July 2013

- Set up for Cane registry entry at gate weigh bridge.
- Notification Creation for IK11 transaction using an exit in background.
- Developed an ALV report which displays to show Stock details with sale order reference.

# **Sundram Fasteners Zhejiang Limited Implementation, China | Dec 2012 – FEB 2013**

- Developed a report for Profit and loss statement and form to print the same as per the client needs in Chinese.
- Developed MOR report and print format for the same in Chinese.
- Developed a statutory report and print format for the voucher printing.
- Created a customized screen for production entry for cold forging and posting the same entry.

# Sundram Fasteners - SAP ECC Financial Consolidation & Vendor Payments Implementation | July 2012 - Nov 2012

- Developed Financial Consolidation Report in Hierarchal format which gives in-depth knowledge about the financial status of the company for all the units starting from Trail Balance, Profit and loss a/c and Balance sheet.
- Developed Final accounts report & Layout which gives details about P&L A/C, P&L appropriation A/C, Assets & Liabilities.
- Automated vendor payment mechanism by fetching all the payment details of vendors for a period and scripting in bank's required format
- Ensured all modes of payment were enabled such as RTGS, NEFT, DD, and CHEQUE.

# **Sundram Fasteners - SAP ECC Support | Jan 2012 – June 2012**

- Developed a customized screen for the Subcontracting GRN and challan reconciliation (Bundle transaction MB01, J1IFQ, J1IF13).
- Implemented a BADI for MIGO to check the quantity.
- Created user exit for VF03, if the billing document is cancelled then user is not allowed view it.
- Created user exit for validating whether costing is done or not for material while PGI is done for delivery.

# Sundram Fasteners - Interactive and Retail portal in SAP ECC 6.0 | Aug 2012 - Dec 2012

- Developed a report to get the pending order details and the output was sent to FTP and the .net team process the file and send to user display.
- Developed a report to for sale order creation using files from FTP.

# Rajshree Sugars & Chemical Ltd, Chennai Implementation Cane Management System in SAP ECC 6.0 | Dec 2010 – July 2011

- Developed an interface with weighbridge to fetch the values directly from meters and post an automated GRN in SAP.
- Developed Complex reports such as cut permit and token generation using module pool programming.

# **Others**

- Received appreciation certificate from GM IT of SIPCHEM for successful completion and delivery of BCM Riyad Bank project.
- Received appreciation certificate from IT Manager of SIPCHEM for successful completion and delivery of PP reconciliation project and showing cost saving for company
- Received appreciation certificate from Shared services GM for Merger activity and project go live.
- Providing ABAP Training and served as mentor for fresher's/internists & co-ops.

## **Personal Details**

Birth date : 27th Aug 1988

**Passport** : **Z3869343** 

Place: Signature
Date: (Nazeer Hussain)